Antonio Gabriel Cuellar Serratos

Ingeniero de Calidad, Mejora Continua (Lean Manufacturing y Six Sigma), Procesos - 34 años

Incorporarme a una empresa en la que pueda aportar mis talentos y conocimientos para lograr la mejora continua en todas las áreas de oportunidad eliminando desperdicios en los procesos buscando que la empresa sea más rentable.

\$25,000 Salario mensual deseado

Guadalajara, Jalisco 44290 Disposición a reubicarse

Área de especialidad

- Ingeniería (Mejora Continua)
- Manufactura, Producción y Operación (Control de Calidad)
- Ingeniería (Ingeniería Industrial)

Habilidades

Office / Manejo, Contratación y Control de Personal / Lean Manufacturing / Core Tools / Minitab / 5s / SGC / Auditorias de proceso

Experiencia profesional

Quality Engineer Customer

Voit Automotive de Mexico Sa de Cv julio 2015 - Actual

ACTIVITIES: Responsible for clients ZF and BROSE. Follow-up of APQP for new projects, attention to clients in the case of complaints or special requirements focused on the area of quality, leader in problem solving and response of 8Ds, coordinate drawing activities in clients' plant, coordinate the activities of quality engineers Processes, generate SPC for the significant characteristics and make meetings to define actions based on results. Update Balance Score Card and KPIs. Perform experimental design.

ACHIEVEMENTS: Consolidate indicators of all customers in the same file to facilitate consultation and better presentation, 50% reduction in time of information capture (daily, weekly and monthly), Reduction of product time in quarantine area, Reduction of QN's, Recognition by Brose for exposing the development of an 8Ds in the week of quality.

Quality Engineer

Sanmina Sci Systems de Mexico S a de C V agosto 2014 - julio 2015

ACTIVITIES: Responsible for the projects of clients CIENA, GENBAND and AFC. Updating Yields and quality metrics. Leader of the CIT. Problem solving and customer complaints. Coordinate Quality Technicians and

Auditors. Updating MPIs and quality routes. Training staff on quality criteria. Support in NPIs. ACHIEVEMENTS: Reduction in time of inspection in CIENA projects, layout re-arrangement achieving reduction in cycle time by 20%, part of the team in pilot run of the products of the customer GENBAND achieving the total satisfaction of the customer from the pieces of qualification.

Quality Engineer Senior

CUPRUM

febrero 2012 - mayo 2014

ACTIVITIES: Responsible for quality issues in the areas of Casting, Extrusion, Tear Down, AMP, APT and CEDIS. Customer Service. Updating documentation, coordination of auditors for product and process release and inspection, SGC audits, internal rejection follow-up (graphs and action plans), follow-up customer complaints, PPM 'S by area and global plant, Green Belt and Black Belt projects, Training new staff, training supervisors in process audits, Monitoring of certification audits, Validation Of datasheets. Leader in selecting six sigma projects in STE teams and follow-up at each stage of the DMAIC.

ACHIEVEMENTS: Consolidate a team, development of multi-skills personnel, documentation of the quality processes carried out in the plant, Implementation of nonconforming product, successful closure of six sigma and operational projects, Black Belt project to reduce plant degradation by 30%. Coach in the successful closing of 2 Six Sigma projects executed by the production leaders.

Black Belt in Continuous Improvement Projects and Quality Systems Engineer

Ferreteria Indar

marzo 2011 - febrero 2012

ACTIVITIES: Documentation of all the processes of the company, Implementation of the LEAN MANUFACTURING methodology, audits of 5's and processes, training to the leaders on problem solving. ACHIEVEMENTS: I directed 5 kaizen in the following areas: Merchandise Receipt, Merchandise Relay, Merchandise Refill, Assortment of Merchandise and Distribution, I implemented the audit of 5's, support to the design of the receipt lay-out, balancing of activities of the staff to accommodate merchandise, implementation of control charts for: time of receipt, waiting time for pallets to be accommodated, products that are not in place, corridors Free (not obstructed with platforms, cars, etc.), among others. Leader of the continuous improvement committee which was created from my income. I made a work plan to document the processes that are needed in all areas (when I entered only the sales processes were documented). I have documented 2 processes of company, I have document control.

Green Belt (Lean Six Sigma) y Leader Auditor SGC

AUTOMOTORES AMERICAS

diciembre 2009 - diciembre 2010

ACTIVITIES: I work under the ISO 9001 and TUV Quality Standards. Implementation of the LEAN SIX SIGMA methodology, process audits, 5's audits, training staff on different methods of problem solving, directing meetings with area managers to review sales objectives, current problems and solutions, Standardization and documentation of processes, generate visual aids, follow KPIs (Key Performance Indicators), train quality personnel to perform functions and present results, responsible for annual ISO audit, programming, review and planning of daily work.

ACHIEVEMENTS: I directed 3 KAIZEN events reaching the objectives in 95%, the most outstanding activities are the reduction of washing time from 17 minutes to 9 minutes, reduction of poorly washed cars (quality) from 36% to 13%, reduction of time of services Maintenance from 4.33 hrs to 2.57 hrs, capacity increase in workshop appointments from 33 to 50 per day.

Quality Coordinator

HENNIGES AUTOMOTIVE

agosto 2007 - diciembre 2009

ACTIVITIES: I worked under ISO / TS 16949 and ISO 14000. Update TPPA charts, follow 8D's, validate and monitor values ??obtained from statistical control points, generate and control quality alerts, generate and control Visual aids, R & R studies, providing clarification of cosmetic standards to operating areas, performing some laboratory tests to validate compliance with required standards, updating quality databases and quality

metrics, Coordinating daily change boards Shift and information boards to production personnel, in the absence of the QE to direct brainstorming meetings, monitoring and filling of logs of each area, update graphs of external and internal faults, verify that product audits are performed, Follow up on deviations, verify the correct filling of scrap formats and first-party releases by auditors and inspectors, conduct QKZ Product Audits, and perform 5'S audits.

LOGROS: Participate in scrap reduction from 12% to 7%. Reduction of 10 to 4 inspectors per shift

Educación

Centro Universitario de Ciencias Exactas e Ingenierías (U de G))

Estudios Universitarios - no titulado en Ingeniería Mecánica Eléctrica con especialidad en Ingeniería de Planta septiembre 2003 - septiembre 2008

: Escuela Politécnica de la Universidad de Guadalajara

Técnico titulado en Técnico Mecánico Industrial septiembre 1999 - septiembre 2003

Idiomas

Inglés Avanzado - Español Lengua nativa

Ingeniero de Calidad, Mejora Continua (Lean Manufacturing y Six Sigma), Procesos antonio.cuellar@live.com.mx Tel: 3331005435

